<resources>
    <string name="app_name">सुraksha</string>
    <string name="title_activity_saving_activity">saving_activity</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="setting">Settings</string>
    <string name="instruction">Instructions</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
    <string name="choose_buttons">Detect Spy</string>
    <string name="instructions">Instructions</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="textwarn">Warning to accept permission</string>
    <string name="guidelines"> <b>1. In Public Places</b>
        \n
\nStay in Well-Populated Areas:  Avoid isolated spaces, particularly after dark.
\nCarry Essentials: Always have a charged phone, emergency contact numbers, and some form of ID on you.
\nAvoid Flashing Valuables: Keep expensive items like jewelry and electronics hidden in public to avoid attracting attention.
\nBe Confident: Walk confidently, with purpose, and avoid appearing lost. Predators often target those who seem unsure or vulnerable.
        \n<b>2. At Home</b>
        \n
\nSecure Your Home: Ensure doors and windows are locked, especially at night or when you are alone. Install security systems or smart locks if possible.
\nUse Peepholes: Verify who is at the door before opening it.
\nKeep Emergency Contacts: Post emergency numbers where they can be easily accessed by everyone in the house.
\nAvoid Revealing Habits: Don’t advertise on social media when you’re alone at home or away on vacation.
\n<b>3. When Driving</b>
        \n
\nPark in Well-Lit Areas: Avoid parking in dark, isolated spots.
\nLock Doors: Always lock your car doors once inside and when leaving.
\nKeep Gas Tank Full: Always have enough fuel to avoid being stranded in unsafe areas.
\nDon’t Pick Up Strangers: Avoid giving lifts to strangers, and don’t engage with aggressive or suspicious drivers.
\n<b>4. In Rideshares or Taxis</b>
        \n
\nVerify the Driver: Check the license plate and driver’s profile on the app before getting into the vehicle.
\nSit in the Back: This provides more control over the situation and a safer exit option.
\nShare Trip Details: Use your phone’s location-sharing feature to inform someone of your journey.
\n<b>5. Online Safety</b>
        \n
\nUse Strong Passwords: Avoid using easily guessed passwords for your accounts. Use two-factor authentication for added security.
\nAvoid Suspicious Links: Be cautious of clicking on unknown links, especially from emails or messages from unknown people.
\nReport Harassment: If someone is harassing or threatening you online, report their behavior to the platform and consider blocking them.
\n<b>6. Handling Uncomfortable Situations</b>
        \n
\nVerbal Assertiveness: Be firm and direct when saying “no” in uncomfortable situations. Don’t feel pressured to explain.
\nSafe Distance: Keep a safe physical distance from people who make you uncomfortable.
\nKnow Basic Self-Defense: Learn simple self-defense techniques or carry safety devices like pepper spray or alarms.
\n<b>7. Emergency Action</b>
        \n
\nCreate an Exit Plan: Always know where the nearest exit is when in unfamiliar places.
\nUse a Code Word: Establish a code word with friends or family to signal that you need help without alerting someone who may be threatening you.
\nScream for Help: In emergency situations, don’t hesitate to scream, draw attention, and run to a safe location.
</string>

</resources>